NM

CONTACT

migelmarshal@gmail.com

+97156-3982449

nigelmarshal.com

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (WITH DISTINCTION): COMPUTER SYSTEMS

2015

Heriot-Watt University -School of Mathematical and Computer Sciences, Dubai, UAE

CODING

React

SASS/SCSS

TypeScript

Javascript

PHP

git

webpack

npm

gulp

Sitecore

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Agile Methodologies

Trello

DESIGN

Sketch

Adobe Photoshop

Axure

LANGUAGES

English (Native) Hindi (Intermediate) Urdu (Intermediate) Malayalam (Intermediate)

NIGEL MARSHAL

Front-End Engineer

ABOUT

I have six years of **front-end development** experience along with **project & technical management** experience; managing outsourced international development teams whilst troubleshooting site issues and client change requests. Most recently I've worked as a front-end developer for the Abu Dhabi Digital Authority where I worked on multiple government entity Sitecore websites and components. I have a strong core in UX, having taken the **HFI UX course** and worked in one of the top MENA UX digital agencies as a **UX Specialist/Developer**.

EXPERIENCE



FRONT-END CONSULTANT/DEVELOPER

Abu Dhabi Digital Authority/ OMNIA | Dec 2019 - Present

- Worked within multiple development SCRUM teams to create numerous government entity Sitecore websites for the Abu Dhabi Government including but not limited to: ADCustom, EMI, QCC, HRA, WRD and ADInspires.
- Created custom modular components for teams to integrate in subsites with customized branding themes.
- Created documentation for developed components and subsites to contribute to the development wiki accessed by multiple vendors.

dubizzle FRONT-END ENGINEER

dubizzle/OLX MENA | Jan 2019 - Nov 2019

- Worked as the sole front-end support for OLX MENA spanning 8 countries, including Lebanon, Egypt and Oman.
- Lead the front-end initiative to implement new paid product features for OLX MENA, to generate passive revenue and for users to boost their ad reach.
- Worked as an integral instructor on a code migration initiative, guiding international colleagues, helping them move to a more advanced and efficient system as well as assist with RTL support.
- Improved, optimized and converted outdated MVC front-end technologies to more robust future proof code.
- Contributed to documentation and wikis for on-boarding new developers.

chbi UX SPECIALIST & UX DEVELOPER

rbbi | Sept 2015 - Mar 2018

- Worked with the core development team in building fully responsive and comprehensive websites with a user centered approach.
- Worked as a hybrid Technical/Project manager liaising with outside vendors for timely client deliverables and code collaboration.
- Possess experience in the UX development workflow such as user research interviews, wire framing, requirement assessment, user testing, project management, development, QA and deployment.
- Handled client facing communications with regards to project progress, change requests and trouble shooting while spearheading development progress.
- Worked closely with cross departments including SEO, Analytics, CRO and Content for websites ranging from landing pages, WordPress websites, webapps and ecommerce.